Gareth Patterson

Charlotte, NC | patteg7@gmail.com | 973 908-9082 | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Being fully self-taught, I have organically cultivated a deep interest in the software space. Coming from a people-oriented background, I find strength in my communication skills. Having served in client facing roles, I am strong in translating business needs into technology deliverables. Likewise, I breakdown complex topics into digestible pieces for stakeholders across all business functions. A track record of exceeding growth expectations in terms of technology and communication. Within just months of learning how to code, I have begun to work on some of the most groundbreaking projects involving ML, LLM, and AI.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend JavaScript | React.js | Tailwind | CSS | HTML Data MongoDB | MySQL. | Machine Learning **Backend** Python | Django. |. Flask. | Node.js **Additional** Networking | Linux | Cloud Computing

Certifications: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900, AWS Certified Developer: Associate Expected October 2023

EXPERIENCE

Endava – IT Service and Consulting

BDR / Software Developer

Charlotte, NC

Jan 2023 – Current

- Implemented space optimization algorithms for a logistics POS project.
- Collaborated as a developer on a Real-Time Payments Fraudulent Payments Detection project using Machine Learning
- Contributed to business enhancement for Data Management, Trading Platforms build-out, Cloud Migration, and AI
- Conducted requirement gathering and facilitated communication between Sales, Delivery, Legal, and Development teams.

Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity Charlotte, NC

Growth Consultant

Jun 2022-Dec 2022

- Calendar and SharePoint Organization for various projects
- Built Excel Budget to track \$400,000 per year using functions and Power Queries

Oxford Networking Systems

IT Analyst

Raritan Center, NJ

Sep 2019-Jun 2022

- Supported internal data networks, enhancing reliability.
- Utilized Linux/MS for remote machine access and network performance troubleshooting.
- Conducted manual hardware fixes to optimize network efficiency.

PROJECTS

Demeter with Endava | GitHub

Jul 2023-Sep 2023

Technologies: Python, Django, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Azure Open AI, LLM,

- Spearheaded the development of an interactive Chatbot, integrating external Azure API.
- Utilized Django to generate a RESTful API, seamlessly connected to an interactive frontend for data visualization.
- Orchestrated the connection of more than 10 models and engineered interactions for optimal functionality.

Dynamic Automatic Stock Execution System | GitHub

Aug 2023—Current

Technologies: Python, JavaScript, Docker MongoDB, Node.js, React, Flask, Yahoo Finance API, ML, Azure

- Real-time data pipeline from Flask backend through to React Frontend, utilizing a RESTful API
- Integrated with Azure Machine Learning to better gauge the predictions of stocks and overall market volatility.
- Currently creating a fully built Machine Learning and Linear Regression Model
- Hosted the system within a Docker container, utilizing MongoDB to store critical data

Coffee & Bean | GitHub

Aug 2023—Current

Technologies: React.js, JavaScript, Tailwind, HTML, CSS, MUI

- Retail site with shopping cart storage system to track items and users
- Utilized a NoSQL server backend that fully integrated with a REST API to React.JS
- Demonstrated the ability to track user flow throughout a typical transactional interaction

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY Software Engineering Expected Oct 2023

Rutgers University New Brunswick, NJ

B.A. in History and Political Science

Graduated May 2022